A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Program Office, Series 26 FA1205
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Program planning preparations and follow-up, 1958-1966; 5; .25 Cubic Feet About .5 LGL sized Hollinger box
  Records within this subseries chiefly pertain to the development of New York State government long-term program planning, the planning processes of different State agencies, and the program planning follow-up documentation and measures prepared by Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's Program Associate Edgar D. Draper and other State staff members. Draper's copy of a program planning follow-up log is included. Handwritten notes have been added to this copy as well as correspondence concerning a follow-up program related to public educational television and the hearings for the 1965 Long-Range Program Planning submissions of the New York State Division for Youth, the New York State Education Department, and the New York State Commission for Human Rights. Other follow-up correspondence and reports included within the subseries pertains to a follow-up program about recruitment and training for professional State jobs.
  - Materials related to Long-Range Program Planning preparations, 1958-1964 (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Program Planning Follow-up log, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Program Planning Follow-up correspondence and reports, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 111, 112)
  - Program Planning Follow-up correspondence and reports, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 113)
- Federal legislation, 1961-1966; 6; .25 Cubic Feet About .5 LGL sized Hollinger box
  Subseries contains copies of federal legislative bills. These bills concern such subjects as education, school prayer, youth employment and delinquency, voting rights and other civil rights matters, hospital insurance, physical and mental health, manpower development, area redevelopment, poverty, Appalachia, and library services. Handwritten notes have been added to several of the bills.
  - Bills, 1961-1966 (Box 12, Folder 114, 115)
  - Bills, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Bills, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Bills, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 118)
- Conference materials, 1963-1965; 7; .75 Cubic Feet About 1.5 LGL sized Hollinger boxes
  Materials found within this subseries pertain to a number of regional, state, and national conferences as well as to the different social, education, economic, and political subjects those conferences concerned. In the course of his duties as Program Associate for Nelson A. Rockefeller's Executive Chamber, Edgar D. Draper attended several of the conferences documented in the subseries. He also worked with other State government staff to prepare background information for Rockefeller's participation at other conferences and to help organize conferences set up by the State and Rockefeller's administration. Files in the subseries primarily pertain to individual conferences, but there are a few that group together documents concerning a number of different conferences on a particular theme such as industry. Common material formats found within the subseries include correspondence, invitations, schedules, programs, press clippings, and reports.
  - Governor's Conference on Aging, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Governors' Conference, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Governors' Conference, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 121, 122)
    1) Fax about the role of the States in education - Folder 122
  - National Negro Republican Assembly, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - New York State Citizens Committee for the Public Schools 13th Annual Conference, 1963-1965 (Box 13, Folder 124, 125)
    1) Buffalo press clippings about school funding - Folder 124 2) Newsday's Back to School Report - Folder 125
  - New York State Citizens Committee for the Public Schools 14th Annual Conference, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - New York State conferences on CUNY College Discovery Program and community colleges, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    1) December 1964 issue of the "Communicator" 2) April 1964 issue of the "Communicator"
  - New York State conferences on education, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    In addition to documents concerning conferences on education, this file also contains materials related to an invitation for a Playboy Club Key application.
  - New York State conferences on industrial growth, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 129, 130)
  - Western New York Invitational Conference on Asia, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - White House Conference on Education, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 132)